<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: analysis-pattern | Trade Off]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.youth2009.org/blog/categories/analysis-pattern/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.youth2009.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-03T23:05:13+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.youth2009.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[dawncold]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[conceptual-models]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.youth2009.org/blog/2013/08/19/conceptual-models/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-19T22:12:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.youth2009.org/blog/2013/08/19/conceptual-models</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Conceptual Models</h2>

<p>Designing software so that its structure reflects that of the problem.</p>

<p>Analysis is not only listing requirments, but also looking behind the surface requirments to come up with a mental model of what is going in the problem.</p>

<p>Conceptual model is a human artifact.</p>

<p>Developers use conceptual models to represent a model of the real world in order to understanding the read part of problems easily.</p>

<p>There is no right or wrong model, merely one that is more useful for the job at hand.</p>

<p>The example, snooker simulation, if your choose a Einsteinian model would be flexible enought to low speed or high speed situation, but the complexity is totally different you know, so the flexibility and many others aspects need a trade-off.</p>

<p>When building a model in a programming language, maybe Python, you may get lost in this language or building this model using some features belong to Python, so this model is a Python-model, and it is hard to be implemented in other languages such as Java, PHP, etc. To avoid these problems, you need a third-party analysis techniques.</p>

<p>Only domain experts could build right model, because of their domain knowledge.</p>

<p>Conceptual model is closely to software interfaces rather than software implementations. One of the important things about OO is that it separates interface from implementation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
